KSHITIJ NIGAM

Cybersecurity Specialist

@ kshitij_nigam@hotmail.com in kshitijnigam @nigamelastic

J +43-6767187059

Vienna, Austria

kshitijnigam.com

nigamelastic

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly skilled and experienced cybersecurity engineer with over 11 years of experience in protecting organizations against cyber threats. Experience in ISMS creation and maintenance for ISO 27001 Certification and SOC 2 compliance. Expertise in performing offensive penetration tests and running SAST, SCA and DAST campaigns for product releases. Experience in industry standard security incident response, vulnerability management, and compliance.

EXPERIENCE

Product Security Engineer, Cloud

Tricentis GmbH

February 2022 - Ongoing

Vienna, Austria

- Lead the ISO 27001 and SOC 2 Type 2 certification of various Tricentis products
- Performing internal penetration tests on Tricentis Products
- Performing and maintaining SCA, SAST and DAST on various Tricentis products to identify the product security posture as part of release readiness.
- Creating and maintaining vulnerability Management Systems for tricentis
- Identifying risks and providing support for creation of Threat Models for **Tricentis Products**
- Provide automated security tools and guidance to product teams and help them integrate in CI/CD pipelines

Security Engineer

Hutchison Drei Austria GmbH

March 2019 - February 2022

Vienna, Austria

- Contributed in creation and maintenance of ISMS for ISO 27001 certification of the company
- Performing internal penetration tests on apps, websites and networks of Hutchison Drei Austria and its subsidiaries
- Provide automated security tools and guidance to product teams and help them integrate in CI/CD pipelines
- Performing regular vulnerability Scans for internal and external assets
- Monitoring networks to identify security breaches and mitigate such incidents using our Security Operation Center (SOC)

QA Automation Specialist Shpock (finderly GmbH & Co.)

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

Vienna, Austria

- Creation of a fully automated cross platform environment using selenium IO, appium and puppeteer using NodeJS with continuous integration using Jenkins
- Creating and Executing Performance Test plan using Jmeter with Selenium plugin using Flood IO
- Creation of Proof Of Concept for Cypress and Travis CI for front-end automation

LIFE PHILOSOPHY

"Change is inevitable but being prepared for it is a choice!"

WHY ME?



Keeping up

As a tech enthusiast I am always excited about the upcoming changes and innovations, hence I always keep an eye on current trends in the industry and adapt to the most efficient solution/method/product



Team Player

I consider being a team player to be one of my greatest strengths, in my professional career I have worked and managed a diverse team spread across physically distant locations. My CTF team is also spread across the world and we work together to solve challenges



Extra Curricular

Apart from my office related tasks, I also indulge in various extracurricular activities such as, CTF competitions, OWASP/Security meetups, hackathons. My CTF-team actively participates in various competitions, you can check out the writeups here: click-me



Open Source

When I find an interesting new technology with better features, I try to utilize it in my workflow. I love to contribute to an open-source project if I find a bug or an interesting feature. These open-source tools/POC/Writups can be found on my github/gitlab account. Notable Tools:

- XSSATTackerPuppeteer **Notable Contributions:**
- ProjectDiscovery
- Kali Linux

Software Development Engineer in Test Tracelink India Pvt. Ltd.

- **July 2016 Oct 2018**
- Mumbai, India
- Creation of Automation Module for Tracelink Inc using, Scala over JAVA, TestNG, Web-Services and Selenium, using Bitbucket as repository
- Automated the Data Entry Process from Physical PDFs using pytesser
- Creating "Functional Requirements" and Tests from Stories in "Pivotal" to manage test campaigns
- Working on effective testing of Dynamo DB(AWS specific) and its interaction of APIs with Lift Framework
- Automation of Feeds dropped on Servers(Habari) and inter-conversion of Maps into various formats.

QA Engineering Senior Technical Associate Avaya

- Feb 2015 June 2016
- Pune, India
- Maintenance of QC and regression campaign. Driving improvements in unit testing coverage and developing test suites for enhancements
- Working closely with feature teams to collect the right data and its utilization in decision making and delegation
- Creation of cross platform end to end automation framework for testing VOIP based products

Validation Engineer Sela technology pvt ltd

- Nov 2012 Feb 2015
- Pune, India
- Creation of Test Specification and Test Cases for Global Platform Messaging
- Creation of testing tool for updating non regression tests using reverse xml parsing using JAVA

EDUCATION

B.E. in Computer Science
Rajiv Gandhi Technical University

July 2008 – July 2012

LANGUAGES

English Hindi German



Recognition in Workplace

- Won The Club Stellar "Rising star award" for best performer in 2015 Avaya Rising Star
- Won Samurai Award for excellent performance in Automation Project and quarterly release in Tracelink 2017
- Won young talent award for best employee in testing team in 2013
- Got appreciation for SP TSM 4.0 Project
- Got appreciation for EU module in Tracelink Web 3.4

TECHNICAL SKILLS

